Register of the Ivan Andreevich Kolchin Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Ivan Andreevich Kolchin papers
1900-1967
2000C49
Hoover Institution Archives
1 microfilm reel (0.15 linear feet)
Correspondence, clippings, and photographs, relating to Russian choirs in China and the United States.
Kolchin, Ivan Andreevich, 1893-1967
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Location of Originals
Originals in: Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco.
Biography
Ivan Andreevich Kolchin was born in Kalinino, Viatskaia guberniia, on 1 August 1893. He received an education in music (specializing in church singing), and by 1910 was already conducting a choir at the Church of St. Nicholas, in the town of Slobodskoi. From 1912 to 1917 he was a student at Kazan' University, managing to find time to conduct the university choir as well. The Civil War forced him into emigration in China, where he once again turned to conducting choirs as a profession, this time earning a worldwide reputation.
From 1921 to 1936, he was the choir director of the Church of St. Aleksei in Mojiagou, China (a suburb of Harbin), and from 1936 to 1940 he was the choir director of the Church of St. Nicholas in Shanghai. At the same time, he trained and conducted his own male choir that toured China, drawing large audiences, winning prizes and achieving some prominence there and abroad.
Kolchin became so well-known for the quality of his work that he was invited to conduct the choir of Holy Trinity Cathedral in San Francisco. He directed this choir from 1940 to 1962, also finding time to direct a Russian male choir that appeared in concert programs throughout California. Kolchin died in San Francisco in April 1967.
Chronology
1893 August 1 Born, Kalinino, Viatskaia guberniia, Russia
1910 Choir director, St. Nicholas church, Slobodsk, Russia
1912-1917 Student, University of Kazan', Russia
1921-1936 Choir director, St. Aleksei church, Mojiagou, China
1935-1940 Choir director, St. Nicholas church, Shanghai, China
1940-1962 Choir director, Holy Trinity Cathedral, San Francisco, California
1967 Died, San Francisco, California
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of clippings, correspondence, scrapbooks and other materials relating to the musical career of Ivan Andreevich Kolchin. Kolchin was a noted church choir director in Kazan', Russia, Harbin and Shanghai, China, and San Francisco, California, as well as director of a Russian male vocal ensemble and music instructor. His performances drew large audiences and he was considered one of the preeminent émigré conductors.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco, as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
China.; Choral societies--China.; Choral societies--United States.; Russia.; Russians--China.; Russians--United States.; United States.
- Biographical File, 1900-1967 (Box 1-2)
  Scope and Contents note
  Certificates of appreciation, clippings, concert programs, scrapbooks and other materials arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Correspondence, 1929-1962 (Box 2)
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent
- Photographs, 1933-1940 (Box 2)
  Nine photographs and reproductions
- Oversize File, 1920s-1962 (Box 3)
  Addresses and posters advertising Kolchin's concerts, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1900-1967 (Box 1)
  - Certificates of appreciation. (Folder 1: 1-2)
    General note
    See also OVERSIZE FILE
    Clippings about or mentioning Kolchin
    - General (Folder 1: 3)
    - Kolchin and his ensemble in Shanghai, 1935-1940 (Folder 1: 4)
  - Concert programs (Folder 1: 5)
  - Diploma (Folder 1: 6)
  - Scrapbooks.
    Includes newspaper interviews with Kolchin and newspaper columns by him, and clippings of reviews of Kolchin's concerts and his musical activities
    - General, 1900-1967 (Folder 1: 7)
      Includes photographs of Kolchin, correspondence, concert programs
    - "I. A. Kolchin v Kharbine, ", 1921-1935 (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - "I. A. Kolchin v Shankhae, ", 1936-1940 (Folder 2: 2)
    - "O pereselenii I. A. Kolchina v Ameriku,", 1939-1940 (Folder 2: 3)
  - Miscellany (Folder 2: 4)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1929-1962
  - General
    - General, 1929-1962 (Folder 2: 5)
    - Congratulatory letters, 1945-1962 (Folder 2: 6)
  - Grechaninov, A., 1951-1954 (Folder 2: 7)
    See also BIOGRAPHICAL FILE/Scrapbooks/General
  - Orlov, I., 1941 (Folder 2: 8)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1933-1940 (Folder 2: 9)
  For other photographs of him, see also BIOGRAPHICAL FILE/Scrapbooks
  Eight reproductions of photographs clipped from periodicals depicting various Russian choirs in the U.S.; one photograph of Kolchin and unidentified individuals at Fort Ross, California.
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1920s-1962 (Box 3)
  - Certificates of appreciation, 1931-1962 (Folder 3: 1)
  - Posters, advertising Kolchin's concerts in Harbin, 1920s (Folder 3: 2)